# KEVIN ADRIÁN RODRÍGUEZ RUIZ

## Full-stack developer

### About me

Chemical engineer and Master in computing with five years of experience in software development.

Self-disciplined person and excited about integrating multiple disciplines and making things easier and accessible.

Knowledge of web applications, Python, Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs and Amazon Web Services.

### Interests

Web applications development.
Bioinformatics. Phenomena Modelling and Optimization. Learning new engineering/science topics.

# Languages

Spanish (native) English (fluent) French (basic)

#### Contact

Bogotá, Colombia. 111156 (+57 1) 6698229 (+57) 3057052399 karodriguezr@unal.edu.co LinkedIn profile GitHub public repositories

#### **SKILLS**

Java, Javascript, Node.js, Python, Reactjs, Amazon Web Services, Spring Framework, Django Framework, Git, Postgres, MongoDB, REST, NoSQL, Scrum, Docker.

Programs: VS Code, Intellij Idea, Aspen Plus.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Consultant (Amaris Consulting, 2019)

+ Oficina en línea. Full stack developer. Web application for the management of insurance policies. Technologies: Reactjs, Redux, Serverless, Amazon Web Services (Lambda, API Gateway, Dynamodb, Redis, CloudFormation).

Software Engineer (Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, 2018 - 2019)

+ ANSEP. Astrocyte Neuron Simulation Environment Platform. Design and development. Web platform for the analysis of genome-scale metabolic reconstructions related to the study of neurodegenerative diseases. Technologies: Python, R, Django, Reactjs, Docker, Postgresql.

Systems Analyst (Software Colombia SAS, 2015 – 2018)

- + SCmail. Design, development and maintenance. Massive email marketing platform. Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs, Gradle, Amazon Web Services (EC2, Lambda, S3, Dynamodb, SES, Autoscale, CodeDeploy, SQS).
- + SCmail upClient. Development and maintenance. Desktop application for the upload of directories/files from a local drive to a repository on Amazon S3. Technologies: Java, JavaFX, AWS.
- + Elogic Monitor. Design, development and support. Desktop application for the generation of digital signatures, encryption, and files upload, it can be invoked from all web browsers. Technologies: Javascript, Java and JavaFX.

#### Academic projects (2017-2019)

- + Rescurves. Design and development. Open source MS Excel Add-in aimed to ease the three-dimensional plotting of residue curves maps for quaternary systems. Technologies: C#, VSTO.
- + Master's final work: CAMD. Design and development. Desktop application to solve the Computer Aided Molecular Design (CAMD) problem of finding the most suitable solvent for a liquid-liquid separation. It makes use of multi-objective optimization and databases mining algorithms. Technologies: Java, Mongodb.

### **EDUCATION**

2016 - 2019	M. Eng. in Systems Engineering and Computing Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)
2018 – 2019	Exchange Student in the MSc in Advanced Catalysis and Molecular Modelling Universitat de Girona (Spain)
2009 – 2015	Bachelor's degree in Chemical Engineering Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)